A Guide to the Leslie T. Webster papers, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Scientific Staff FA204
Rockefeller Archive Center
Leslie T. Webster papers, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Scientific Staff
1919-1943, undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Webster, Leslie Tillotson
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
FA204
0.5 Cubic Feet 1 box and 1 volume
Biographical/Historical note
Leslie Tillotson Webster, 1894-1943, physician and researcher worked in epidemiology and bacteriology at The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research from 1920 until his death in 1943. He was a pioneer in the investigation of the importance of natural resistance to disease and the experimental facts on the basis of which the spread of epidemics can be explained. Author of book "Rabies" published in 1942.
Biographical note
1894 Born July 23 New York, N.Y.
1915 A.B. Amherst College, Amherst, Mass.
1919 M.D. Johns Hopkins Medical School, Baltimore, Md.
1919-1920 Assistant Resident Pathologist, Johns Hopkins Hospital
1919-1920 Assistant in Pathology, Johns Hopkins Medical School
1920-1923 Assistant (Pathology and Bacteriology) Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, New York, N.Y.
1923-1927 Associate, RIMR
1927-1934 Associate Member, RIMR
1934-1943 Member RIMR
1935 Sc. D. (Honorary) Amherst College
1935 Prize of 1000 francs Univ. of Berne Medical Faculty (Research in encephalitis)
1943 Annual Award from Dog Writers' Association (Outstanding service to dogs in field of medical research)
1943 Died July 12, Scarsdale, New York
Member of: Society of Experimental Biology and Medicine, American Society for Experimental Pathology, American Epidemiological Society, American Association of Pathologists and Bacteriologists, Harvey Society, Society of American Bacteriologists, American Association for the Advancement of Science, American Public Health Association, Alpha Delta Phi, Alpha Omega Alpha, Phi Beta Kappa
Scope and Contents note
Administrative correspondence; biographical information; bibliography; diary; film.
Consists primarily of administrative correspondence, copy of diary (1929-1943), notes on "Experimental Epidemiology" and silent film left to The Rockefeller University by Mrs. Webster.
Also includes Leslie T. Webster's 1919 diary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 W395
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Medicine, Preventive; Biochemistry; Biology -- Research; Medical research; Diseases; Medical sciences; Epidemiology; Bacteria; Bacteriology; Epidemics; Life sciences; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Webster, Leslie Tillotson; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University
- Biographical material (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Bibliography; photographs; some newspaper clippings; Memorial Minute.
- Reprint: Archives of Pathology 36 (1943) 536-537 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Obituary note written by Peter K. Olitsky (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Diary, 1929-1943 May (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Reproduced typed copy.
  Includes thoughts on family life as well as on progress of laboratory activities and world affairs.
- Administrative correspondence, 1920-1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Primarily with Simon Flexner and Business Manager and deals with budgetary matters, laboratory workers and assistants; laboratory equipment, supplies, animals and projected research plans.
  Includes original application for appointment and recommendation by Dr. W.G. MacCallum of Johns Hopkins University, (holograph).
  Items of special interest.
  - To Simon Flexner from L.T. Webster stating he will not accept offer in pediatrics made by Dr. Park of Johns Hopkins Hospital, 1927 March 31
  - Poliomyelitis epidemic in Los Angeles, 1934; 28 items
- Experimental epidemiology, 1926-1940 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Headed: "Older notes 1926-1940 (about 40 pages)" Photocopy assembled from handwritten notes; tables and reprints. [Maybe draft of 1946 posthumous publication].
- Experimental epidemiology film, 2 copies No. 42041 silent 16 mm film (Box 1)
  Study of epidemic patterns in a rabbit colony.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Film left to the Rockefeller University by Mrs. Webster.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
  Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
- Diary by Leslie T. Webster in Labrador, 1919; 1 volume (circa 1 inch)
  Biographical/Historical note
  In May 1919 Dr. Leslie T. Webster graduated from John Hopkins Medical School second in his class and left for Labrador with his classmate Dr. Charles Parsons.
  Printed by his widow, Emily de Forest White.